# **Adrian Grimm**

https://adriangrimm.com https://github.com/usmcamgrimm Massillon, OH | (386)438-3487 usmcamgrimm@gmail.com

#### **Profile**

I am a front-end developer passionate about writing clear, semantic HTML, CSS and JavaScript that follow design and Web Accessibility standards, with an extensive history of open-source collaboration using Git which includes front-end and Android development. My experience also includes exposure to front-end frameworks such as React and Gatsby. A Marine Corps veteran, I value teamwork and collaboration and I am motivated to learn and grow my skills.

#### **Education**

Vets Who Code Sept 2019 – Feb 2020

• Program: Front End Developer Bootcamp

• Coursework: Responsive Web Design, Accessibility, React, Gatsby, Algorithms and Data Structures

Stark State College May 2020

• Certificate: Web Design & Development | GPA: 4.0

Coursework: SQL(MSSQL and Oracle DB), HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, WordPress

# **Projects**

Portfolio Website: https://adriangrimm.com

HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Grocery-List: <a href="https://groceries-list.netlify.app">https://groceries-list.netlify.app</a>

HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Havamal Band Website: https://www.havamalband.com

ReactJS, GatsbyJS, Sanity CMS, Tailwind CSS, Styled-Components

#### **Experience**

# Securitas Electronic Security and Diebold, Inc.

Aug 2012 – Present

Senior Programming Specialist

Monitoring Operations Center Dispatch Representative

- Provided technical support for technicians in the service and installation of alarm and video equipment.
- Assisted field technicians with detailed technical support for access control systems.
- Utilized and maintained a SQL database for a card access system and generated reports.
- Successfully and efficiently responded to alarm signals generated by automated monitoring software.

## United American Security: Lieutenant / Site Supervisor

Aug 2011 – Aug 2012

- Effectively led, managed, and trained a team of corporate security officers assigned under my direction.
- Created and provisioned access cards for Diebold associates and contract employees.

## **Corrections Corporation of America:** Correctional Officer

Feb 2010 - July 2011

- Exercised care, custody, and control of offenders assigned to serve sentences of incarceration.
- Assisted in multiple inmate cell extractions as a member of the Special Operations Response Team.

**United States Marine Corps:** Towed Artillery Systems Technician

Jan 2002 - Jan 2010

Billets included: Instructor, Battalion Ordnance Officer, Battalion Ordnance Chief, Artillery Section Head

- 2007, Fallujah, Iraq: Ensured security for Battalion and Company level staff.
- 2002-2008, Camp Lejeune, NC: Effectively managed readiness of the Battalion's artillery assets.
- 2003, 2005, Iraq, various locations: Instrumental in maintaining unit combat effectiveness.
- 2008-2010, APG, MD: Trained and mentored entry-level Marines as Artillery Repairmen.